Kitasan Black is in the lead now.
好的 现在领先的是北部玄驹
She's still maintaining her lead on the slope.
上坡之后 北部玄驹还是拼命维持领先地位
200 meters left.
剩下200米
Opheryu is following closely behind.
巨星俳优紧追在后
-So is Sounds of Earth. -Go!
-万籁争鸣也死死咬着 -冲啊
Kitasan Black is not giving her lead up.
即便如此 北部玄驹还是一样领先在前
Sounds of Earth takes the second spot.
第二名是万籁争鸣
Sounds of Earth!
万籁争鸣
The 3rd place, Cheval Grand, closes the gap too.
第三名高尚骏逸也追上来了
But Kitasan Black is too far ahead.
但是领先的北部玄驹
Kitasan Black!
北部玄驹
She did it!
她办到了
I did it. I did it!
成功了 我成功了
-Kita! -Congratulations!
-小北 -恭喜啊
What a thrilling race!
这场比赛 真是令人兴奋
Second place in G1. Well done!
GI第二名 干得好啊
Not bad at all.
结果还不错
Right? She's amazing.
是啊 真是厉害
Right…
是…是啊
I'm running out of things to teach her.
我已经没东西能教她了吧
Third place…
第三名…
VERXINA, VIVLOS
(极峰　强击)
I did it.
我成功了
Yes. You worked so hard for it.
是啊 你真的很努力
Three wins in G1. And it's Japan Cup to boot.
第三个GI冠军 而且还是日本杯
Not bad. You won first place in the biggest event of the year.
居然在这最大的舞台赢下冠军 还挺厉害的嘛
Arima Kinen is next.
好 接下来就是有马纪念
I will have my revenge!
我要报上次的一箭之仇
UMA MUSUME PRETTY DERBY SEASON 3
《赛马娘 Pretty Derby 第三季》
EPISODE 7: OUR ARIMA KINEN
(第7话 我们的有马纪念)
Who did you vote for in Arima Kinen?
有马纪念的票 你投给谁了
"ARIMA KINEN FAN VOTING" I voted for Kitasan Black and Cheval Grand.
(有马纪念粉丝投票) 我投给北部玄驹和高尚骏逸
They are the veterans.
资深级的话就是她们了吧
But for the Classics, it has to be Satono Diamond.
如果是经典级 那肯定就是里见光钻
She performed so well in Kikuka Sho.
她在菊花赏时的表现超强的
She has it in her. She just needed the stars to align.
她一直都很有实力 只不过很不走运罢了
They are strong enough to represent the current generation.
她们彼此都有着 足以代表该世代的实力
I can't wait to watch their duel.
真是期待她们的对决
Third place in Japan Cup. You were so close.
日本杯第三名 真是可惜
But you did so well too.
不过你表现得也很棒了啊
Congratulations.
恭喜你
Oh… Thank you.
嗯 谢谢…
It's been a while since we last hung out like this together.
总觉得我们三个 很久没像这样聚在一起了
You weren't there for my previous celebration party too, Cheval.
我上次的庆祝会 高尚你也没来呢
Sorry, I was busy.
那个时候我刚好有事…
Eh? I see.
咦 是这样吗
You did win
最后的后冠赛
Triple Tiara's Shuka Sho. So well done to you too, Vivlos.
你有赢下秋华赏 真是太好了 强击
Gentildonna always outruns me.
我跟老是被贵妇人压着打
Unlike you who can never score above second place.
只能一直拿第二名的姐姐不同呢
Hey. Watch your mouth.
真是的 你还真敢说啊
Cheval, are you participating in Arima Kinen?
高尚接下来是要参加有马纪念吗
I guess.
是啊 算是吧
Then, win your first G1 in Arima Kinen.
高尚 就在有马纪念 赢下你的第一个GI冠军吧
It'd be great if all three of us could become horse girls in G1.
要是三姐妹 都能成为GI赛马娘就好了呢
Mhm.
真的
-Let's eat something good before training. -Only the runners-up race in Triple Tiara.
-今天吃些好吃的 再来好好练习吧 -三后冠赛事全都是第二名
-Sure. -Verxina reigns in Victoria Mile.
-嗯 好 -姐姐在维多利亚一哩赛中连霸
-Wow. -And Vivlos had already
-好厉害 -连妹妹强击也比我更早赢下GI
I'm the only one who hasn't…
只有我什么都还…
-Cheval, if you won't eat it, I'll… -I can't lose anymore.
-高尚 你要是不吃 我要拿了哦 -不能再输了 不能输给任何人
"FUKUNAGA COMMERCIAL STREET" There you go.
(福永商店街) 好 这样就行了
Thank you for your help again, Kita.
谢谢你每次都来帮忙啊 小北
We shouldn't ask a horse girl who won G1 thrice to do this anymore.
让GI三胜赛马娘来做这种事 真是不好意思
It's okay. I don't mind it.
不会 没事的 请不用在意
Congratulations Kita, on winning Japan Cup.
小北 恭喜你赢下日本杯
Thank you.
谢谢
I voted for you in the fan-voting contest.
上次的人气票选 我投了你一票呢
Do your best in Arima Kinen.
有马纪念要加油哦
I will. I can't wait to run with Diamond.
好的 今年可以跟光钻一起上场 我超期待的
We'll be there to cheer for you.
大家得一起再去帮你加油才行呢
I, for one, can't wait to watch the post-race concert.
我们也很期待赛后的 WINNING LIVE呢
Whether I win or lose…
无论是输还是赢…
No.
不对
I won't lose.
我当然是不会输的
I will make sure to give my best performance on live!
我会将最棒的LIVE献给大家的
Go, Kita, the festival girl.
哦 祭典小北
-All right. -Go, Kita, the festival girl.
-好的 -哦 祭典小北
-I won't let you down.
-包在我身上
FINISH LINE
(终点)
Kita is in great shape.
北部的状况看起来不错呢
Mhm.
是啊
She'll put on a better performance than last year's in Arima Kinen.
没错 看来能够期待她 表现得比去年有马纪念更好
I can't wait.
还真是令人期待呢
Kitasan will be a tough foe to beat.
看来北部很不好对付呢
Yes.
是的
Done.
好
Kita!
小北
Do you have any plans later?
等一下你有打算要做什么吗
No.
没有耶
Do you want to hang out with me?
那要不要来陪我一下
-Delicious! -So delicious.
-好喝 -太好喝了
You're in a great mood today.
你的状况不错嘛
Yes, I feel good about myself.
是的 感觉情绪也很高昂
I can't wait
我真的很期待
to race alongside Diamond in Arima Kinen.
能够跟光钻一起参加有马纪念
I see.
这样啊
It's all because of you, Teio.
这都是因为帝皇哦
Me?
因为我吗
Yes.
是的
That was an unforgettable Arima Kinen.
那场有马纪念 真的很厉害
It was memorable.
很惊人
Everyone watched you
所有人都在看着帝皇奔跑
cross the finishing line.
在冲过终点线的瞬间
You were like a shooting star.
你像是在赛场上被光芒包覆般 闪闪发光
I lived through
那个时候
that moment,
我看到了
the moment a star was born, cheered by everyone else like my dad.
看到跟爸爸一样的所有人 目睹了明星诞生的瞬间
It was dazzling. Surreal.
闪闪发亮 像是梦境般美妙
It's a scene I'll never forget.
那种在心头挥之不去的景色
So I vow
以及我许下了诺言
to one day
有朝一日
race in this grand stage.
一定要一起在这种大舞台上奔跑
I will do my best
用尽彼此的全力
and bring everyone a race as memorable as that day.
比出一场跟今天一样的比赛
Diamond and I grew up together.
我和光钻从小就一起长大 感情非常好
We always let each other have the last piece of food. Or we just share it.
如果东西只有一个的话 我们会让来让去 或是一人一半
But the first place of Arima Kinen…
但是有马纪念的第一名
I can't let her have it. Nor can we share it.
无法让给她 也不能一人一半
I had a bad run in Arima Kinen last year.
去年的有马纪念我饮恨败北
And in the past year,
这一年里
I've been working really hard to improve myself.
我努力练习 拼命取胜 累积实力
I've never defeated Diamond in a match,
我从以前到现在
be it running or rope skipping.
无论是赛跑还是跳绳 我都没赢过光钻
But not this time. This time,
但是这一次 这一场比赛
I'll win.
我一定要赢
You're all set then.
看来你没问题呢
Huh?
咦
Sometimes, the better you feel about yourself,
因为有时状况越好
the more disappointed you'll be. Because you get carried away.
就越是会空欢喜一场 让你看不清楚周围
Teio…
帝皇…
Do your best, Kita.
你要加油哦 小北
All right.
是
If I win in Arima Kinen,
如果我真能赢下有马纪念的话
I can perhaps be the Horse Girl of the Year.
或许我能成为 年度表代赛马娘也说不定呢
Eh…
那个…
I'm getting carried away, aren't I?
这样有点太得意忘形了吧
HONG KONG G1 VICTORY CELEBRATORY BANQUET
(香港GI称霸纪念庆功宴)
Who would have thought that you would bag your first G1 overseas?
想不到你的第一个GI 居然会是在海外拿到的
Right?
我也是这么想
But
不过…
it wasn't until I won my first race
赢下之后我才明白
that I realized the burden and joy of winning G1.
赢下GI的那份沉重与喜悦
Crown…
皇冠…
It's all thanks to you, Diamond.
这都是多亏了光钻呢
You broke our family curse during Kikuka Sho.
因为你赢下了菊花赏 打破了里见魔咒
Well…
那种事…
The other Satonos are in great spirits lately.
最近里见的其他孩子 状况也很不错对吧
I think it's because you just became the new ceiling they want to break through.
我还听说是因为光钻 创造了新的魔咒呢
We have to hurry up and break the ceiling then.
那就得快点打破它才行呢
But thank you truly, Diamond.
不过谢谢你 光钻
Your performance in Kikuka Sho rekindled my spirit.
就是因为你在菊花赏的表现 点燃了我的斗志
Not at all, Crown.
不是的 皇冠
You took the words out of my mouth.
这是我要说的话
I can't lose this time.
我也觉得不能输
Next year, I want to challenge the world.
明年我也想要向世界挑战
Therefore, in the upcoming Arima Kinen,
所以这次的有马纪念
I must defeat her.
我有个无论如何也要赢过的对手
Kitasan, you mean?
你说的是北部吗
It's a shared promise between you two, isn't it?
你们小时候有立下诺言对吧
To one day participate in Arima Kinen together.
要一起参加有马纪念
The promise is important to me.
那当然也很重要
But
不过…
I need to defeat who I think is the strongest now
我现在要打倒我认为最强的对手
and become the best horse girl in Japan.
拿下国内最强的称号
I will represent Japan in tournaments
然后成为 不辱日本代表身份的赛马娘
and bring our family this honour.
将这至高的荣耀献给里见
It's my goal.
我要亲手完成它
Diamond…
光钻…
UMA MUSUME PRETTY DERBY SEASON 3
《赛马娘 Pretty Derby 第三季》
Earth, you're doing great.
争鸣 状况不错哦
Easy-peasy.
没问题 轻轻松松
How confident are you for Arima Kinen?
那你有马纪念有信心吗
Very confident, Mademoiselle Nature.
当然没问题了 素质小姐
Heed my words. I will
我可以向你们保证
deliver a jaw-dropping performance like Golden Ship did last time.
我将会展现出如同上次 黄金船那让观众欢呼般的表现
Golden Ship was ranked 8th last year.
黄金船去年不是第八名吗
That's not good.
那样不行啦
How valiant!
很英勇啊
I don't understand what she said
虽然听不懂她在说什么
but there's no denying her confidence.
但感觉她很有自信呢
Kitasan Black!
是北部玄驹
This is her fourth G1. And she's giving her all.
北部面对第四个GI 也是卯足了劲呢
Yes. She's very strong.
是啊 她超强的
As expected from a horse girl personally acknowledged by Turbo.
不愧是涡轮认可的对手
Her growth has been spectacular since spring.
她从春天开始就飞速成长呢
Mhm.
的确
Miss Nature.
优秀素质老师
Give me another lesson when you have the time.
有空请让我再找你讨教哦
Another lesson?
老师…
-She's… -She teaches Kitasan Black?
-那一位… -是北部玄驹的老师…
Wow.
好厉害
Did she just say that you're her teacher?
她为什么要叫你老师
Colour me surprised.
不要问我啦
Sheesh. Kitasan outdid herself again.
真是的 北部那个家伙 冲过头了吧
This will be our match, Diamond.
终于要一决胜负了呢 光钻
This will be our match, Kita.
终于要一决胜负了 小北
You, who always follow behind me.
光钻从小就一直跟在我的身后
You, who always hold my hands
小北从小就一直牵着我的手
as we visit different places.
带我去看各种风景
Diamond is strong, beautiful, and elegant.
光钻她有资质 又强又帅又漂亮
And so…
所以…
The stage is ready, Kita.
舞台已经准备好了 小北
I will win.
我一定会赢的
The winner will be me.
赢的人一定是我
Uhm… Are you awake?
那个 你还醒着吗
Yes, I am.
是啊 我还醒着
I want to sleep but I can't.
明知道要快点睡却睡不着
It feels like the night before a school trip.
就像是明天要去远足一样呢
Speaking of school trips, when I toppled my lunch box,
说到远足 我当时把便当打翻的时候
you shared your lunch with me.
小北你把便当分了一半给我呢
Did I?
是这样吗
But we can't share the first place.
第一名没办法一人一半呢
Yeah.
是啊
Diamond.
光钻 我啊
I have always thought that you are an amazing person.
从以前就一直觉得你真的很厉害
Whenever I do something,
就算是我先开始做某件事
you always manage to catch up to me easily.
每次你都能马上追上我 而且还做得得心应手
You're so bright.
你的天质聪颖
You're like my younger sister but you're smart and so capable.
明明像是我的妹妹 却又如此聪明厉害
I really can't wait to race against you.
一想到要和这样的光钻一决胜负 让我真的很期待
Me too.
我也是…
Kita, you always work so hard.
小北一直都很努力
You never give up and you face everything with a smile.
不论遇到什么事都不会受挫 都会笑着去面对
You lift us up.
让大家充满活力
And I think that's incredible.
我觉得真的很了不起
Diamond…
光钻…
We should sleep now.
得快点睡了呢
Goodnight.
晚安
Diamond!
光钻
Ah, it was just a dream.
原来是作梦…
What time is it now?
现在是几点
Phew.
太好了…
Eh?
咦
Diamond?
光钻
I'M OFF. -DIAMOND
(我先出发了 光钻)
I see.
这样啊
Our race has already begun, right, Diamond?
这表示我们之间的比赛 已经开始了对吧 光钻
All right then.
好
So cold!
好冷
In this wintry Nakayama Racecourse, all horse girls are fired up.
在年末寒风中的中山竞马场 吹起各自的热烈信念
The annual Arima Kinen is about to begin.
好的 一年一度的有马纪念 又要开始了
I am excited.
真的很令人期待呢
What spectacular moments can we expect in this year-end grand event?
这场年末大奖赛 会出现什么样的名场面呢
There's a huge crowd today.
今年也有这么多人
It's December but I can feel the heat.
明明已经12月了 却依然热情不减
Right?
是啊
Today is the day.
终于来了
They are here.
她们出来了
Kitasan Black is voted as the fan's favourite
赛前投票是北部玄驹赢得第一
but more people cheer for Satono Diamond today.
但当天的人气选手则是里见光钻
Who are you supporting?
你要为谁加油
You already know the answer.
你这是明知故问
SATONO DIAMOND, KITASAN BLACK
(里见光钻 北部玄驹)
We think alike.
心照不宣呢
As expected, these two are the most anticipated horse girls.
最受瞩目选手果然还是这两位
Yes.
是的
Will Satono Diamond, who grabbed her first G1 win in Kikuka Sho
是在菊花赏中完成了GI夙愿
and who has the most fans in the Classics, win?
在经典级中 呼声最高的里见光钻会赢
Or will it be Kitasan Black, who has also won Kikuka Sho
还是一样在之前的菊花赏中 获得优胜
and who now has three G1 wins under her belt?
现在有着GI三胜光环的北部玄驹 会展现那资深级的实力呢
This end-of-year grand prix…
年末的大奖赛…
I'm as ready as G-sharp.
现在的我 就像是在G弦上
I cannot underperform
在那两人的面前
before them.
我不能跑出丢脸的比赛
Never.
绝对不行
The race will begin soon.
好的 比赛马上就要开始了
Diamond.
光钻
Diamond, we will…
光钻 我们要…
We will race with all our might
我们要比出一场好比赛
and settle the score.
堂堂正正决一胜负吧
I will defeat you,
我会赢你的
Kitasan Black.
北部玄驹
Diamond is very focused.
光钻 她的精神非常集中
I cannot lose to her.
我也不能输
I wonder, what does 100,000 fans
这十万人的欢呼
sound like to those horse girls at the starting line?
听在起跑点上的赛马娘们的耳里 是种什么样的声音呢
All runners are in position.
选手们陆续在闸门就位
What race awaits us today? What will we witness?
今天会是场什么样的比赛 会看到什么样的名场面呢
Arima Kinen.
有马纪念
And they're off!
现在起跑了
Kitasan Black is off to a good start on the inside line.
内侧的北部玄驹起跑得相当不错
Next to her is Opheryu.
而巨星俳优就跟在她的旁边
Go!
冲啊…
The one in the lead is Read Fantasy.
在领先争夺战中 最先夺得优势的是阅览奇幻
Kitasan Black is right behind her.
北部玄驹就紧跟其后
Satono Diamond is middle of the pack.
而里见光钻则在中段位置
Green Uniform is running as fast as possible too.
绿色赛衣正在不停向前奔驰
The cheers of 100,000 fans will welcome these horse girls soon.
十万人的欢呼声正迎接着赛马娘们
After the fourth bend of the first lap, they arrive at the stretch.
通过第一圈的第四弯道后 来到最初的非终点直线
Read Fantasy is still in the lead.
领先的是阅览奇幻
Kitasan Black takes the second spot.
北部玄驹独自位居第二
Behind her are Opheryu and Great House.
而巨星俳优和雄伟之屋 则是紧跟在她的后方
What a thunderous sound.
好惊人的声音
That's Arima Kinen for you.
这才是有马纪念嘛
Mhm.
是啊
Not bad.
状况不错
But don't get impatient, Kitasan.
但是别太急躁了 北部
The race stabilizes after the first bend.
进第一弯道 场内的赛况暂时稳定了下来
The time record for the first 1,000-meter lap is 61 seconds.
最初的1000米时间为61秒
Read Fantasy continues to maintain her lead.
阅览奇幻以轻快的节奏领先在前
No. 1, Kitasan Black,
在6至7马身的后方
is six to seven lengths behind her.
就是1号北部玄驹
Am I too fast?
是不是有点太快了
No, I should be able to handle this speed with my current stamina.
不对 这种速度 对现在的我来说不是问题
Transfixed by Kitasan Black, Satono Diamond takes the third spot.
接着是有如盯上了北部玄驹一般 来到第三名位置的里见光钻
The runner-up from the previous year,
6号万籁争鸣
No. 6, Sounds of Earth, is here too.
去年的第二名赛马娘在这里
-Earth! -No. 6, Sounds of Earth, is here too.
-争鸣… -去年的第二名赛马娘在这里
No. 14, Cheval Grand, closes the gap too.
14号高尚骏逸也追上来了
Go!
加油…
They are heading to the third bend. 600 meters left for this race.
进入第三弯道 比赛剩下不到600米了
I can do this. I can do this.
我办得到…
Charge!
我只能上了
Read Fantasy's lead is almost all gone.
好的 领先的优势几乎消失
Kitasan Black is half a horse length behind her.
北部玄驹追到了半个马身的位置
She slowly overtakes her.
渐渐地超了过去
She plans to accelerate?
打算加速甩开吗
Not bad.
但是还不错
-Overtake her. -Go!
-就这样冲过去 -超越她
All the best, Kita.
加油啊 小北
After the fourth bend, they are now at the final stretch.
过了第四弯道 终于来到了最后直线
The cheers from 100,000 fans rock through Nakayama Racecourse.
十万观众的欢呼声 再度震撼了中山竞马场的草地
Is this the end for Read Fantasy?
阅览奇幻撑不住了吗
Kitasan Black continues to accelerate.
北部玄驹持续加速
Opheryu gives chase.
巨星俳优紧跟着北部玄驹
Then, it's Satono Diamond.
接着是里见光钻
Cheval Grand closes in too.
高尚骏逸也追上来了
These popular horse girls bolted to the front.
这些人气赛马娘 全都一口气冲到了前方
I can see the finishing line.
看到终点了
Kitasan Black braces herself
北部玄驹要一决胜负了
and goes for the final sprint.
开始进行最终冲刺
-Go! -and goes for the final sprint.
-冲啊 -开始进行最终冲刺
Will she turn this race into a festival about her victory?
她有办法将年末的中山竞马场 变成祭典会场吗
However, she cannot widen the gap.
但是没办法拉开差距
The ones at the front will not give up.
领先集团的一众选手也紧追不放
How long can Kitasan Black maintain her lead?
北部玄驹撑得住吗
Satono Diamond appears.
里见光钻追上来了
She's here, but…
她来了 但是…
Kitasan Black continues to accelerate.
北部玄驹再度展开加速
This is it.
就这样…
You always outrun me,
虽然每次都被你追过去
but not today.
但是今天你别想追上我
Satono Diamond approaches.
里见光钻紧追不舍
Kitasan Black speeds up again, but Opheryu has given up yet.
北部玄驹再度加速 巨星俳优也不甘示弱
Satono Diamond continues to close in.
里见光钻追上来了
It's a race between the three most popular horse girls.
是三大人气赛马娘的竞争
Keep it steady.
要撑住
I must run faster.
要追上
Has she done it? Has she overtaken her?
能追上吗 她能追过去吗
She did! With a tiny margin!
以些微之差从外侧超越了
Satono Diamond!
里见光钻
Satono Diamond won this race.
在这场激战中胜出的是里见光钻
She showed the veterans what she is capable of.
她让资深级 见识到她那觉醒的才能了
Eighth place?
第八名吗
I like the sound of it.
不错的旋律
Eighth place! You did so well!
第八名 你很努力了
Congratulations, Diamond.
恭喜你 光钻
Thank you, Kita.
谢谢你 小北
You're so strong.
好厉害
So very strong.
你真的很厉害
You're very strong too, Kita.
嗯 小北也很厉害
Well, I still can't outrun you.
真是的 果然还是跑不赢小北呢
You tested my limit too.
我也赢得不轻松
I'm so used to chasing after you.
因为我一直都在追逐小北的背影
I see.
这样啊
Do your best in the concert too.
WINNING LIVE也要加油哦
I promised my friends that I would give them the best performance.
我答应过蔬果店的叔叔们 要给他们看看最棒的LIVE呢
Sure.
好
It's our first time on the same stage together, Diamond.
和光钻一起登台也是第一次呢
Yeah. I'm a little bit nervous.
是啊 有点紧张呢
Me too.
我也是
When this happens, you can write the character, festival, on your…
这种时候啊 就要在手上写个"祭"字…
Kita, it's about to begin.
小北 要开始了
Right.
好
Even though I enjoyed the race,
虽然是场好比赛…
she is still ahead of me.
但那个背影依然在我眼前